Welcome all of you to Kar Saath channel. Today the
video we will cover is in print. There is
news that ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance has partnered with a small
finance bank. So when we understand
that ICICI Bank is such a big bank, even then it
needed to partner with a small finance bank.
What is bank insurance? What is bank
insurance? And
what is a small finance bank.
We will be looking for the answer to all these three questions in this video. So first let us understand
what is bank insurance. As
you can see the definition, bank insurance
is a partnership between a bank and an
insurance company that allows the bank to sell
the insurance product to its customers. What does
this mean? What will the bank and the
insurance company do? Suppose there
is a bank and there is an insurance company, what will the
insurance company do? It will partner
with the bank and what will the bank do? It will
sell whatever
insurance product is there to the bank's customers. Okay, so now
you understand bank insurance. Now let us understand what a
small finance bank is. Small
finance bank.
As you can see the definition here. Small
finance bank. Small finance bank
can  Provide the basic banking facility of
acceptance of deposits and lending.
What does it mean? It can take deposits, meaning it
can take money, it can even lend land.
What does land mean? It can give loans.
Okay, and the aim behind providing
financial inclusion is to bring financial inclusion
to the section of the
economy that is not served by other
banks. There are other banks like II Bank and
SBI Bank, which are
not able to do financial inclusion. What does financial inclusion
mean? People should have at least
one bank account in the bank. They have to be
included in the bank. So, it means
financial inclusion for whom, like
small business units, small and
marginal farmers, farmers, they should be
included. It will cover micro and small industries and
unorganized sectors, as
you might know, like there is SBI Bank
or II Bank, where are all these banks located?
Their branches are
not many in rural areas, they have
more branches in urban areas
because they see profit there but where are the
small finance banks mostly located, they are
in urban areas,
their job is to serve them
in urban areas like farmers or
small and micro industries or
unorganized sectors, it has been created to help them
and to include
people financially, okay so now let us
understand next why did this IIC Bank feel the
need to
partner with small finance, as you must know that
I have already told you that
you must have seen almost all the branches of IIC Bank, they are
in urban areas,
if you are from rural area then you must
know that IIC Bank mostly does
not operate in rural areas, why does it not operate,
as I already told you that it is
because of profit, and you can see,
I have put the photo of IIC Bank here, now do not
focus on the girl, focus on IIC Bank,
if it has to send insurance to rural areas,
which insurance does it have its own
Prudential Life Insurance, so what it will do is it will
open its branch in rural areas.
Now, who knows how many rural
areas there will be where it will not
open its branch everywhere. So what will it do in that case,
it will partner with someone like a
small finance bank. Small finance banks
already have rural branches, so it will
partner with small finance banks and
sell its insurance. So what will the small finance
bank benefit from this? The small finance
bank will take a commission. If someone
works like an agent, what will it do? It will
sell the insurance to the customers. Whatever
small finance bank Ujjivan Small Finance Bank
already has customers, it will
sell the insurance to them and whoever
sells the insurance to their customers will earn money from it
as a commission. Okay, that small finance
bank will benefit from this. And even the ICICI
Bank, they have to sell their insurance. They are able to
sell it in urban areas
but are not able to sell it in rural areas. So, those who are
not able to sell in rural areas will also be
able to sell it. So, now you must be wondering whether
Ujjivan Small Finance Bank is the
insurance company of ICICI.  It will
not sell anything like that. As I already told you
what Ujjivan Small Finance Bank is, it is an
agent, so what will be its job, to
sell insurance of other banks as well. As
you can see, which banks it sells to,
this is not important from an exam point of view,
but you should know
like you can see Bajaj Ella
Life Insurance, Aditya Birla ADAC Life
Insurance, Max Life Insurance, now
IIC Potential Life
Insurance has also been added to its list. Okay,
next let's talk about
why Ujjivan Small Finance Bank does
n't create its own insurance product, then
it will be more profitable if it sells insurance as well.
Okay, and the commission, that is, the
profit that is going to be made from the insurance, that is what it will get.
Now
why can't it do that? We understand under
which jurisdiction the bank comes. It comes under RBI,
which regulates the RBI, which is the parent
bank of all, RBI. Similarly,
RBI also regulates the small finance bank. But if
Ujjivan Small Finance Bank wants to
sell insurance, then it will have to get the
license from the Insurance
Regulatory and Development Authority.  One will have to
take a license from the Board of India, so firstly the
procedure for getting this license is very big
and on top of that whom is Ujjivan Small Finance Bank
helping, it is
not covering the section of society in which not
much profit is available, so firstly there is
no profit and on top of that if you go to other
places and take the burden of insurance on
yourself then it will become more difficult, so that is why
it is doing its banking work
and it is gaining its profit from the insurance base it is getting,
okay so that is all
for today in the video, I
tried to explain to you all the three
points, you must have understood them, so that is all
for today, thank you for
watching this video.